Damian M. Garcia

damianmgarcia.com

GitHub Repositories

Summary

Entrepreneurial software developer with two years of experience independently learning, planning, designing, writing, testing, debugging, documenting, deploying, and supporting high-quality, one of a kind software solutions, including browser extensions, progressive web applications, websites, and plugins using agile methodology. An experienced and highly-accomplished pharmacist with strong leadership, analytical, mathematical, scientific, and problem-solving skills determined to pivot into and bring these strengths to the field of tech.

Experience

Software Developer

Self — San Antonio, Texas

2021-09-01 to Present

Independently designed, developed, tested, and deployed five one of a kind software solutions within one year of taking initiative to learn and apply fundamental computer science concepts, including programming, object-oriented design, data structures, algorithms, and the software development lifecycle.

- **Hide n' Seek** <u>Website</u> <u>Repository</u> <u>Video Demonstration</u> A featured and highly-rated MV3 extension published on the Chrome Web Store with over 250 users. Being beautifully and thoughtfully designed, its users are treated to an intuitive, accessible, and delightful experience that gives them the ability to hide companies and promoted jobs on LinkedIn and Indeed. It also features device-to-device syncing and works with all global variations of LinkedIn and Indeed. All marketing materials, including the branding, promotional video, images, and graphical assets, are original work.
- MomentaMouse Website Repository Video Demonstration A plugin created for web developers that allows them to give their mouse-using visitors the ability to magically flick through websites as if they were on a phone or tablet. It features inertial scrolling and a bouncy, harmonically damped overscroll that feels natural and familiar. Designed to be easily customizable and compatible out-of-the-box, it works well with standard and custom HTML elements, and even in complex scenarios that feature nested scrollers with varied scroll axes.
- SmoothScroller Website Repository Video Demonstration A plugin created for web developers that gives them a powerful smooth scroll method that outclasses standard smooth scroll methods. It features customizable scroll duration and easing and, most importantly, emits events and returns asynchronously so that web developers can write code that reacts at any point, from beginning to end, of a smooth scroll.
- Personal Website Website Repository Video Demonstration A custom, responsive, and accessible personal website that features a completely original design, logic, logos, vector artwork, animations, cancelable actions, media carousels, and dark and light modes. No third-party frameworks or libraries were used. Domain and DNS are managed with Google Domains and hosting is managed with GitHub Pages.
- Charm's Jobs Website Video Demonstration A custom and responsive audiobook progressive web application that works online
 and offline and features beautiful, original artwork, animations, dynamic backgrounds, and intuitive media and page-turning controls,
 including gesture-based navigation. No third-party frameworks or libraries were used. Domain and DNS are managed with Google Domains
 and hosting is managed with Microsoft Internet Information Services.

Captioning Agent

CaptionCall — San Antonio, Texas

2019-12-23 to 2023-06-29

Provided excellent customer service to hearing-impaired telephone users by captioning a variety of conversational topics verbatim with high levels of speed, accuracy, and strict consumer confidentiality in a remote, high-volume call center.

Pharmacist

Internships — San Antonio, Texas

2018-07-02 to 2019-05-10

Lead and managed pharmacy teams and workflows in various settings, including community and hospital pharmacies. Effectively communicated evidence-based, complex pharmaceutical information to audiences of varying health literacy, from patients to physicians, in written and verbal forms. Optimized safety and efficacy of medication regimens using data-driven approaches, and counseled and immunized patients in high-volume pharmacies. Critically analyzed medical literature and clinical trial data in reports that were presented to health care professionals.

Education

Doctor of Pharmacy (PharmD)

The University of Texas — Austin, Texas

2015-08-26 to 2019-05-25

Graduated with a class rank of #1 of 126 students from one of the most competitive pharmacy programs in the United States, which ranked third best nationally in 2015.

- Class rank 1 of 126
- Pharmacy GPA 4.0
- PCOA score highest in class, ranked 99th percentile nationally
- PCAT score ranked 99th percentile nationally

Skills

Languages — CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Python, SQL, TypeScript

Tools — Adobe After Effects / Illustrator / Photoshop / Premiere Pro, Boxy SVG, Git, GitHub, Microsoft Excel / IIS / PowerShell / Visual Studio Code, Node.js, SketchUp

Processes — 3D modeling, agile, animation, back-end development, documentation, front-end development, graphic design, photo editing, scripting, version control, video editing, waterfall, web server administration, writing

2023-07-08 Page 1 of 1